-相信这个人可不是明智之举  -我能应付他
- Trusting this man is not a good idea. - I can handle him.
时管局删除过很多这种人  没有任何两个是一样的
The TVA has pruned a lotta these guys, and no two are alike.
洛基
你们都是时间异体
You're all Variants!
时间守护者没创造你们
The Time-Keepers didn't create you.
他们从时间线里绑架走了你们
They kidnapped you from the timeline.
前情提要
你俩引起的关联事件
The nexus event the two of you caused,
不管是什么  都能摧毁这里
whatever that connection is, can bring this whole place down.
好吧  你想知道真相吗
Fine. You want the truth?
我是想保护你
I'm trying to protect you.
我们之间的友谊非常罕有
Friendship like ours is uncommon.
如果我去哪里都可以  你知道我会去哪吗
You know where I'd go if I could go anywhere?
去我真正的家乡
Wherever it is I'm really from.
在时管局来之前  我生活的地方
Yeah, wherever I had a life before the TVA came along.
删除他
Prune him.
时间守护者夺走了你们的人生
The Time-Keepers took your lives from you.
你们都是时间异体
You're Variants.
我们是一样的
We're the same.
无意识的机器人
Mindless androids.
那是谁创造了时管局
Then who created the TVA?
茜薇  有件事我得告诉你
Sylvie, I have to tell you something.
你要一五一十地告诉我
You're gonna tell me everything.
人人影视
原创翻译  双语字幕
翻译|校对    杏仁斯嘉丽  Eunice
字幕组招新中
请访问 YYSubs.com
时间轴    大葱  树    后期   吉吉     总监       草草
时间变异管理局
时时刻刻  永永远远
这是什么地方  我们这是在哪  你们是谁
What is this place? Where are we? Who are you?
这里是虚空  那是玉衡
This is The Void. That's Alioth.
我们要成它的午餐了  快走
And we're his lunch. Come on!
洛基
第一季第五集
给我你的时空器
Give me your TemPad.
-时管局背后究竟是什么人  -我跟你一样一头雾水
- Who's really behind the TVA? - I'm as in the dark as you are.
可怜的伦斯雷尔法官  你的整个现实都被摧毁了
Poor Judge Renslayer. Your whole reality's been destroyed.
告诉我  在另一边是什么感觉
Tell me, how does it feel to be on the other side of it?
就是这里  对吧
This is it, isn't it?
你偷了我的生活之后就拖我到这里
This is where you dragged me after you stole my life.
那我在这里夺走你的生命也再合适不过了
A fitting place, then, to take yours.
要是我告诉你洛基没死呢
And what if I said Loki wasn't dead?
目前还没
Not yet, anyway.
-那你就是在撒谎  -也许吧
- I'd say you were lying. - Maybe.
又或者我们有相同的目的
Or maybe we want the same thing.
他怎么可能还活着
How is he still alive?
救下他
And how will saving him
怎么就能让我们接近时管局的真正控制者
get us closer to who's really behind the TVA?
说来复杂
It's complicated.
-我是自愿告诉你这些的  -为什么
- I'm telling you this willingly. - Why?
因为我想知道顶层的是谁
Because I wanna know who's at the top of this.
我想知道谁对我撒谎了
I want to know who lied to me.
我们删掉分支现实时
When we prune a branched reality,
不可能清除其所有物质
it's impossible to destroy all of its matter.
所以我们把它转移到时间线上的一个地方
So we move it to a place on the timeline
它不会再继续生长
where it won't continue growing.
基本上  分支时间线不是被重置了
Basically, the branched timeline isn't reset.
-而是被转移了  -转移到哪里
- It's transferred. - To where?
时间尽头的虚空
A void at the end of time.
每个存在的实体都在同一处发生碰撞
Where every instance of existence collides at the same point
然后停止
and simply stops.
为什么
Why?
我不知道
I don't know.
教条说时间的尽头依然在被书写
The dogma states that the end of time is still being written,
时间守护者正将其转化成乌托邦
that the Time-Keepers are transforming it into utopia.
很好  非常可信
That's nice. Super believable.
不管真正的原因是什么
Whatever the real reason...
没有东西从那里回来过
nothing ever comes back from there.
如果你相信我  我可以帮你
I can help you if you trust me.
我们先喘口气吧
I suggest we take a quick breather,
这样我就可以提几千个问题
so I can ask several thousand questions.
得继续走  不然会死
Gotta keep moving so we don't die.
这我支持  但你的计划是什么
I can get behind that, but what's your plan?
-不死  -明白  但除此之外呢
- Don't die. - Okay, understood. But beyond that?
-不死  -这不叫计划
- Don't die. - Don't die isn't a plan.
这是活着的一般性要求
It's a general demand of living.
如果你们是洛基  就应该随时有...
If you're Lokis, you should always have...
谁能给我解释下这到底是怎么回事
Will someone please explain to me what the hell is going on?
听着  过去几天非常非常非常艰难
Look, it's been a very, very, very trying past few days.
还是几个月  我都不知道纽约之后过了多久
Months? I don't even know how long it's been since New York.
我只知道我被删除了  醒来就在这里
All I know is, I got pruned and I woke up here,
我现在被自己的时间异体包围了  还有一只鳄鱼
and now I'm surrounded by Variants of myself, plus an alligator,
我说出这句话都要心碎
which I'm heart-broken to report
我竟然不觉得这一切奇怪
I didn't even find all that strange.
现在我们为了躲避那鬼东西  不知道要逃到哪去
And now we're running from God knows what to God knows where.
而我该做的是设法回到时管局
When what I need to be doing is trying to find a way back to the TVA.
别号了  会把玉衡招来的
Stop wailing or you will signal Alioth.
你是说天上那个妖怪吗
You mean the monster in the sky?
谢谢
Thank you.
时管局把垃圾倾倒在这里
This is the place where the TVA dumps its rubbish,
他们删除的一切
everything they prune.
而玉衡
And Alioth,
它的作用是让一切有来无回
he ensures none of it ever returns.
它是一场活的暴风雨  消耗物质和能量
It's a living tempest that consumes matter and energy.
他们把一个完整的分支现实送到这里
They send entire branched realities here
瞬间就被吞噬了
that are devoured instant -
我们在鲨鱼缸里  玉衡就是那条鲨鱼
We're in a shark tank. Alioth is the shark.
没有鳄鱼缸这种东西
Oh, there's no such thing as an alligator tank.
再说  这个比喻更好
Besides, it's a better metaphor.
他只是跟我们一样过于敏感了
He's overly sensitive like the rest of us.
等等
Hang on,
-你是说那玩意也是个洛基吗  -对
- you're telling me that thing's a Loki too? - Oh, yes.
好吧  我愿意接受  为什么有这么多洛基
Okay, fine. Willing to accept that. Why are there so many of you?
因为洛基总能活下来  这就是我们的特质
Because Lokis survive. That's just what we do.
-很好  那我们怎么逃出去  -我们不逃
- Great. So how do we escape? - We don't.
我们都是被时管局抓起来删除的  和你一样
All of us were arrested by the TVA and pruned, just like you.
和你现在做的一样
And just like what you're doing right now,
我们都曾干站着  做着行不通的糟糕计划
we all stood around making bad plans that went nowhere.
但要是我们能用上时空器
Yes. But if we could use a TemPad.
唯一能轻易让我们逃出去的那东西吗  是啊
Oh, the one thing that could easily get us out of here, yes.
它们到处都是  对不对  朋友们
They're all over the place, right, guys?
好吧  那引起一起关联事件怎么样
Fine. What about causing a nexus event?
时管局不在乎这里发生了什么
The TVA doesn't care what happens here.
-但我们肯定能做些什么吧  -有
- Surely there's something to do. - There is.
活下来  就这么简单  从来都是如此
Survive. That's all there is. All there ever was.
别说了  走吧
We're done talking. Let's go.
你想怎么做就怎么做吧
Just do what you want, I guess.
好吧  等等
Okay, wait, wait, wait.
你凭什么戴着角  你听一个小屁孩发号施令
Why do you wear the horns? You let a child command you.
你最好尊重这个孩子
You'll do well to respect the boy.
-这里是他的王国  -好吧
- This is his kingdom. - Right.
你的关联事件是什么  陛下
What was your nexus event, Your Majesty?
我杀了托尔
I killed Thor.
话说  你为什么这么想回到时管局
So, why did you want to return to the TVA so badly, anyway?
你把你的光荣使命留在那里了吗
You leave your glorious purpose there?
差不多吧
Something like that.
分钟小姐  我要你远程访问
Miss Minutes, I need you to remote access
档案中的一系列保密文件
a series of restricted files from the archives.
天啊  什么文件
Ooh, doggy! On what?
关于时间初始  时管局建立
The beginning of time. The founding of the TVA.
-马上  -等等
- Right away. - Wait.
-那时间的尽头呢  -只是虚空
- What about the end of time? - It's just a void.
如果虚空不是尽头呢
What if The Void isn't the end?
如果那之外还有什么呢
What if there's something beyond it?
藏在天启的阴影中  使我能躲过时管局
Hiding in the shadow of apocalypses obscured me from the TVA
因为在那里我无法创建时间分支  对吧
because I couldn't create a diverging branch there, right?
那么  如果这一切依然在被书写
So if all of this is still being written,
不管发生什么  都只是一条新时间线
whatever happens is just a new timeline.
在那里不可能开启关联事件
It would be impossible to start a nexus event there.
-可以完全不被人发现  -就是这样
- You could be completely undetectable. - That's it.
他们只可能在那里
That's the only place they could be.
那我们怎么越过虚空
So how do we get past The Void?
不可能
It's impossible.
时空器找不到切入点  没有目的地
There's nothing for the TemPad to lock onto, no destination.
那我们自己穿过去
Then we go through it.
-那等于自杀  -那看来我就用不到你了
- That's suicide. - Then I guess my need for you has passed.
等等  虚空飞行器能用吗
Wait. What about The Void spacecraft?
对  那台原型机
Yes, the prototype.
好  我去找文件
Great. I'll get the file.
那是一艘为能抵御时间虚空而设计的飞船
It's a spaceship designed to withstand the temporal void.
也许能带我们到时间尽头
It could conceivably take us to the end of time.
-找到洛基  -找到幕后的人
- Find Loki. - Find the man behind the curtain.
-杀掉他  -一起
- And kill him. - Together.
分钟小姐  关于这时间飞船的文件呢
Miss Minutes, where are the files on this timecraft?
还在找  亲爱的
Still lookin', hon.
没有结果吗
Nothing?
埋得可真深啊
Buried pretty deep.
它高度保密  我可能都没有权限
It's highly restricted. I might not even have clearance.
不  你肯定有  如果它真的存在
Oh, no, I think you would. If it's real.
还要多久
How long?
快了
Any second now.
快快快  上
Go! Go! Go! Move it!
-你受伤了吗  -我没事  但她拿走了我的时空器
- You hurt? - I'm fine, but she took my TemPad.
茜薇  你不是想逃走吧
Sylvie? Not thinking of going on the run, are you?
我们知道你藏在哪
We know where you hide.
我们迟早会抓住你
Sooner or later, we'll catch you.
你肯定身心俱疲吧
It must be so exhausting.
我承认  你有那么一下子真骗到我了
I'll admit you had me fooled there for a minute.
还是你说的是真心话
Or did you get a little real?
伦斯雷尔法官真觉得被她敬爱的时管局背叛了吗
Did Judge Renslayer really feel betrayed by her beloved TVA?
你出来吧  我们好好谈谈
Why don't you come back out and we can talk about it?
好啊  你让所有人都离开
Sure. Just tell everyone else to piss off
就我们俩解决
and we can settle this between us.
我觉得行
Works for me.
说好的"找到幕后的人"呢
What happened to finding the man behind the curtain?
不如这样吧  你高举双手出来
Tell you what. You come out with your hands up
我就把你关进时间循环
and I'll put you in a time loop.
选一段不太糟的
Something not so bad.
你就可以在美好回忆中度过余生
You can live out your days in a good memory.
你有美好回忆吗
Do you have any good memories?
只有一段
Just one, really.
-她删除了自己  -很好
- She self-pruned. - Good.
那她也死了
Then she's dead, too.
罗克斯葡萄酒
我击败了美国队长和钢铁侠之后
So, after I vanquished Captain America and Iron Man,
赢得了我的奖品  六枚无限宝石
I claimed my prize, all six Infinity Stones.
这是鳄鱼低吼着说"骗子"
That's alligator for growling and saying "Liar" at the same time.
至少我的关联事件不是吃了惹不起的邻居的猫
At least my nexus event wasn't eating the wrong neighbor's cat.
-给他们讲讲你的经历  洛基  -我吗
- Tell them your story, Loki. - Me?
没人想听
Nobody wants to hear about that.
其实我想听
I would, actually.
我在想  因为我...
It's just I've been wondering, because I'm...
我们应该死掉  不是吗
Well, we're supposed to die, right?
诸神黄昏之后  灭霸杀了我们
Thanos kills us after Ragnarok.
灭霸
Thanos?
在我的时间线里
In my timeline,
我这辈子一切都顺顺利利的
everything proceeded correctly, my entire life,
直到灭霸袭击了我们的飞船
until Thanos attacked our ship.
这么说你没试图用刀刺杀他吗
So, you didn't try to stab him?
当然没有
Certainly not.
别见怪  朋友们
Take no offense, my friends,
但在洛基的巫术面前  利刃不值一提
but blades are worthless in the face of a Loki sorcery.
它们妨碍了我们的魔法潜能
They stunt our magical potential.
-但利刃看着很帅  -是啊
- But they look awesome. - Oh, yes.
尤其是在你脖子被拧断之前
Especially when they clatter to the ground
刀哐啷一声落在地上时
just before your neck is snapped.
我造了一个自己的逼真投影
I cast a projection of myself so real,
连疯狂泰坦都信以为真
even the Mad Titan believed it.
然后我像无生命的碎片一样藏起来
Then hid as inanimate debris.
我假死之后  就在宇宙里漂流
After I faked my death, I simply drifted in space.
远离托尔  远离一切
Away from Thor, away from everything.
思考宇宙真谛和我在其中的位置
Thought about the universe and my place in it,
然后我发现  不管我去哪
and it occurred to me that everywhere I went,
都只会带来痛苦
only pain followed.
于是我将自己抽离出来
So I removed myself from the equation,
在一颗偏远的行星上落脚
landed on a remote planet
然后孤独地待在那里
and stayed there in isolation,
住了很久很久
in solitude for a long, long time.
时管局是怎么找到你的
How did the TVA find you?
我感到寂寞了
I got lonely.
说实话  我想我哥哥了
To tell you the truth, I missed my brother,
我想知道他和其他人有没有想我
and I wondered if he missed me, if anybody else did.
但我一离开那颗行星
But as soon as I took my first steps to getting off the planet,
时管局就到了
the TVA arrived.
因为我们只有一个角色要扮演
Because we, my friends, have but one part to play,
弃儿之神
the God of Outcasts.
仅此而已
Nothing more.
弃儿之神
The God of Outcasts.
-我要走了  -去哪
- I'm going. - Going where?
逃出这里  逃出虚空  回到时管局
Out of this place, out of The Void, back to the TVA.
我们虽然擅长活下去  但也擅长逃跑
We may be good at surviving, but we're also good at escaping.
反正也是个不错的机会
I wager that gives me a decent chance as any.
-哪样你都做不成  你会被残忍杀死  -随便吧
- You won't do either, you'll be brutally murdered. - Well, so be it.
-反正从一开始那就是我的命运  -你不一样
- That was my destiny to begin with. - You're different.
-为什么  -不  我没什么不同
- Why? - No, I'm not, you see?
我是一样的  跟你们所有人一样
I'm the same, really. I'm the same as all of you.
你们碰到过女性洛基时间异体吗
Have any of you met a woman Variant of us?
-听着好吓人  -她确实吓人
- Sounds terrifying. - Oh, she is.
但这也是她的伟大之处
But that's kind of what's great about her.
她才是与众不同
She's different.
她不是想夺下时管局
She's not trying to take over the TVA,
而是想扳倒它
she's trying to take it down.
她需要我
And she needs me.
你说玉衡把我们困在这里
Now, you said Alioth is what keeps us here.
你说它是活物  你说它是鲨鱼
You said it's a living thing. You said it's a shark.
既然是活物  就会死
Well, if it lives, it dies.
所以我要灭了鲨鱼
So I'm gonna kill the shark.
我要杀掉玉衡  我能得到的帮助越多越好
I'm gonna kill Alioth, and I could use all the help I can get.
太好了
Yeah, baby. Yeah.
-冷血怪物  -太好了
- Monsters. - Oh, yeah.
你好  你是我们中的哪一个
Hello, which one of us are you?
这真是一场噩梦
This is a nightmare.
是你
You.
关门  我们还没完全脱险
Shut the door, we still got a little bit of a situation here.
你应该小心点  别随便跳上陌生人的车
You should be careful just jumping into a stranger's car like that.
-小心  -我看到了
- Watch out! - I see it, I see it.
是吗  因为你就冲着它开过去了
Really? Because you're driving right towards it.
天啊  你可真是个名副其实的洛基
God, you really are one of you.
坐稳了
Hang on.
你个混蛋  你引狼入室
You bastard! You led the wolves to our door.
太空任务
跟狼相比  我们更喜欢被称为毒蛇
We prefer snakes to wolves.
我两种都吃过  它们同样会死
I've eaten both. They die just the same.
对不起  陛下
Apologies, my liege.
我背叛了你  现在我是王
I betrayed you, and now, I'm king.
关于这事
About that...
-你不是认真的吧  -拜托
- You can't be serious. - Come on.
-你以为呢  -我们说好的不是这样
- What did you expect? - That was not the bargain!
我供出我们的藏身处  以换取庇护所和供给
I gave you our location. In exchange for shelter and supplies,
你把军队给我  我登上王座
you give me your army and I take the throne.
对
Ah, yes.
这约定不太划算
Not so good a bargain.
这样如何  军队和王座都归我
How about this one? My army, my throne?
关于这事
About that.
你们这群愚钝  磕碜的卑鄙小人
Why you beef-witted, half-faced scrubs.
-我们说好了的  -老天
- We had a deal! - For God's sake.
这里怎么会有只鳄鱼
Why the hell is there an alligator in here?
他是个洛基
He's a Loki!
光荣使命
Glorious purpose!
来啊
Come on.
接招  洛基
Take that, Loki!
该死  一群禽兽
Damn it! Animals, animals!
我们撒谎  欺骗
We lie and we cheat,
我们割破每个信任我们的人的喉咙  为了什么
we cut the throat of every person who trusts us, and for what?
权力  荣耀的权力  光荣的使命
Power. Glorious power. Glorious purpose!
我们死性不改
We cannot change.
我们支离破碎  每一个都是  永远如此
We're broken, every version of us. Forever.
任何一个洛基一旦鼓起勇气改邪归正
And whenever one of us dares try to fix themselves,
都被送到这等死
they're sent here to die.
所以我才需要离开这里
That's why I need to get out of here.
什么都无法改变  除非时管局被制止
Nothing can change until the TVA is stopped.
-你信任她吗  -她是我唯一信任的人
- And you trust her? - She's the only one I do trust.
现在
And right now,
我相信她是我们制止时管局唯一的机会
I believe she's our only chance of stopping the TVA.
我觉得这就够了
That's good enough for me.
好的  我们会帮你
Okay, okay. We'll help you.
但接近玉衡
But approaching Alioth
等于自寻死路
is a death sentence.
我们会带你过去  但不会再多做什么了
We'll get you to it, but that's as far as we go.
一直以来  我真心相信我们才是好人
All that time, I really believed we were the good guys.
毁灭整个现实  让小女孩变成孤儿
Annihilating entire realities, orphaning little girls,
经典英雄作风
classic hero stuff.
当你认为只要目的正当  可以不择手段
Well, I guess when you think the ends justify the means,
你什么都做得出来
there's not much you won't do.
顺便说下  你也毁灭了不少东西
By the way, you did some annihilating too.
-我是迫不得已  -我也是
- I did what I had to do. - Yeah, so did I.
你把我当狗一样追杀
You hunted me like a dog.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry about that.
我删除自己时  以为也许能找到洛基
When I pruned myself, I thought I might be able to find Loki.
那团风暴  那玩意  很可能已经杀了他
That storm, that thing, it's likely already got him.
你真这么想吗
You really believe that?
我怎么想不重要
It doesn't matter.
现在唯一重要的是离开这里
The only thing that matters now is getting out of here
找出幕后黑手
and finding out who's behind all of this.
很好  我们怎么做
Great. How do we do that?
调头
We turn around.
调头  回愤怒云团那吗
Turn around? What, and go back to the angry cloud?
对  它可能就是答案
Yeah. I think it might be the answer.
我们必须回去
We're going back to it.
我必须说
I have to say,
走向那团巨物  感觉很怪
it feels odd walking toward the gargantuan creature.
你有行动计划吗
Do you have a plan of action?
进入它  找到它的心脏或大脑之类的
Get inside, find its heart or brain or whatever,
-然后在里面动手  -我觉得...
- and then, you know, do it in. - I mean...
虽然这计划不复杂  但不代表就不好
Ok, just because it's not complicated doesn't mean it's bad.
但也不代表是好计划
It also doesn't mean it's good.
瞧  他赞成
See? He's on board.
他是在祈祷  他认为我们死定了
He's praying. He thinks we're going to die.
全体船员到战斗岗位
All hands to battle stations!
玉衡和其他动物一样
Alioth is like any animal.
它会先追逐大餐
He'll go after the big meal first.
趁它忙着猎捕时
And while he's busy with that,
我们可以偷溜到它后面  然后
we can sneak around the back and...
开炮
Fire!
好吧
Okay.
也许我们
Maybe we, uh...
再考虑周全些
think a bit more about this, huh?
有车
Car.
-什么  -沿着地平线开来
- What? - Along the horizon.
那是坏事吗
Is that bad?
通常是食人劫掠者
Well, usually means cannibalistic marauders
或食人海盗
or cannibalistic pirates.
真开心
Delightful.
现在他们减速了
Now they're slowing down.
-他们在干什么  -保持警惕
- What are they doing? - Just stay on guard.
茜薇
Sylvie.
我不明白  他是懦夫还是之前很勇敢
I don't understand. Is he a coward or was he being brave?
-我不太确定  -走吧
- I'm not too sure. - Come on.
你还活着
You're alive.
发生了什么  你没事吧
What happened? You okay?
莫比乌斯
Mobius!
-你们怎么...  -我们认为你需要增援
- How did you... - We thought you could do with some backup.
不  等等  他们是我的朋友
Oh, no, wait, wait, wait, these are my friends.
他们是...  怎么说比较好
Well, they're, um... How best to put this?
孩子时期的我们  未来的我们
Us as a child, us in the future,
和鳄鱼版的我们
and us as an alligator.
最好别问了
It's best not to question it.
随便扔块石头都能砸到个洛基
You throw a rock out here, you hit a Loki.
所以你们也在追捕巨云怪物
So you're all after the giant cloud monster, too, then?
我们还没决定怎么杀死它  但是...
Well, we haven't decided how we're going to kill it, but...
-你说什么  杀死它  -对  我们要杀了玉衡
- Sorry. Come again? Kill it? - Yes, we're gonna kill Alioth.
天啊  这就是你的计划
Oh, my God. That was your plan.
-是的  -你们都听他的
- Yeah. - And you all went along with it?
-我有过疑虑啦  -很可能不安全
- I was... I had my doubts. - Probably unsafe.
好吧  那你的计划是什么
All right, well, what's your plan, then?
我认为我们要找的人
I think the person we're after
就在时间的尽头的虚空之外
is beyond The Void at the end of time.
如果真是这样
And if they are,
那怪物就是他们的看门狗  保护着唯一的入口
that thing is just their guard dog protecting the only way in.
好吧  那我们怎么越过看门狗
Okay, so, um, how do we get past the guard dog?
我要用魅术控制它
I'm gonna enchant it.
-那太疯狂了吧  -有多疯狂
- That's insane, right? - As insane as what?
-和把巨云当剪纸剪死一样疯狂吗  -听着
- Paper-cutting a giant cloud to death? - Listen,
-我来这里的时间比你久一点  -我要对它施魅术
- I've been down here a bit longer than you... - I'm going to enchant it.
她相当有自信
She's pretty confident.
下去吧
Leave us.
为什么把我关在这
Why am I locked in here?
你放走了那个时间异体
You freed the Variant.
-你背叛了时管局  -背叛
- You were disloyal to the TVA. - Disloyal?
-你以为你能逃脱惩罚吗  -背叛谁
- Did you think you'd escape punishment for that? - Disloyal to who?
你去过时间守护者的房间  他们不是真的
You were in the Time-Keepers' chambers. They weren't real.
那又能改变什么
And why do you think that changes anything?
那改变了一切
That changes everything!
人们需要知道真相
The people need to know the truth.
不  时管局需要稳定
No, the TVA needs stability.
在我们弄清楚这是怎么回事之前
And until we can figure out what's going on,
必须维持稳定
that is what it will get.
所以你得把一切都告诉我
So you need to tell me everything.
你到底想要我怎么样
What exactly do you want from me?
你和那个时间异体连接过
You had a link with the Variant.
告诉我  是什么在驱使她
I want you to tell me what drives her.
复仇驱使着她
Revenge drives her.
杀死时间守护者
Killing the Time-Keepers.
但他们其实是假的  你可别忘了
But they turned out to be fake, in case you forgot.
所以她会寻找创造他们的人
So she'll be searching for whomever created them.
你根本不是为了保护时管局  对吧
This isn't about protecting the TVA at all, is it?
你也想找出在背后搞鬼的人
You just want to find whoever is behind all of this, too.
你永远也找不到的
You'll never find them.
不会比她早
Not before she does.
为什么
And why is that?
你只是想找到
You only want it.
而她必须找到
She needs it.
你们好啊
Hey, y'all.
我要关于时管局建立的所有文件
I need all the files on the founding of the TVA.
从时间初始开始
Everything from the beginning of time.
这要求很难办
Well, that's a mighty tall order.
创建这地方的人有危险
Whoever created this place is in danger.
我得找到他们
I need to find them.
好吧  马上去办  女士
Okay. Right away, ma'am.
你真的不记得他了吗
You really don't remember him?
时管局逮捕了很多个洛基
I mean, the TVA arrested a lot of Lokis,
不过我不记得有只鳄鱼
but, no, I don't remember an alligator.
谁能断定他是洛基时间异体呢
I mean, who's to say he's even a Loki Variant?
他是绿色的
He is green, isn't he?
我说不好  他有可能在撒谎
I don't know, he could be lying.
放长线钓大鱼  当然了
The long con. Of course,
那他就更有可能是个洛基了
that just makes him more likely to be a Loki.
你们总是设下重重圈套
It's always the game within the game
我很佩服
with you guys, which I respect.
莫比乌斯
Mobius,
假设你真回到了时管局
assuming you do get back to the TVA,
你会陷入什么麻烦
what exactly are you getting yourself into?
我不知道
I don't know.
我想让人们知道真相
I'd like to let people know the truth.
你就这样轻易背叛
So just like that, you're turning on the very thing
你毕生致力于的事业吗
you devoted your life to.
改变永远为时不晚
Well, it's never too late to change.
但愿他们知道自己在干什么
I hope they know what they're doing.
莫比乌斯不算太坏
Mobius isn't so bad.
也不算很好
Or so good.
所以我们才处得来吧
I think that's why we get along.
他在乎你
He cares about you.
很冷
It's cold.
如果你想  我可以变出一件给你
I could conjure one for you, if you like.
你可以帮我变套新衣服
Tell you what. You could conjure me a new outfit.
你不知道这种衣服有多不舒服
You have no idea how uncomfortable something like this is.
那么
So...
莫比乌斯和他的理论...
Mobius and his theory about...
对  关于我们的关联事件
Right, right. About our nexus event.
-根本是胡扯  -当然了  绝对是瞎说
- Total rubbish, right? - Absolutely. Of course. I mean...
我并不是说那一刻不美好
I don't mean that it wasn't a, you know, nice moment.
没错  那很棒  很美好
No, it was great. It was really nice.
只是听起来又是时管局的谎言
It just sounds like another TVA lie.
百分之百  绝对的  嗯
A hundred percent. I mean, totally. Yeah.
我不知道该怎么做
I don't know how to do this.
我甚至不知道我们在做什么
I don't even know what we're doing.
我没有朋友
I don't have friends.
我没有...
I don't have...
同伴
anyone.
反正
Well...
有更重要的事  不是吗
you know, there are more important things, right?
对  像扳倒时管局
Right? Yeah. Like bringing down the TVA.
甚至是拯救宇宙
I mean, saving the universe, even.
没必要那么夸张  不过也算是吧
Well, there's no need to be dramatic, but, yeah, kind of.
不是很舒适
It's not very snuggly.
-好吧  -是桌布吗
- Okay. - Is it a tablecloth?
不  是张毯子
No, it's a blanket.
谢谢你
Thank you.
不客气
My pleasure.
我怎么知道在最后时刻你不会背叛我
How do I know that, in the final moments, you won't betray me?
听着  茜薇
Listen, Sylvie, I...
我背叛了所有爱过我的人
I betrayed everyone who ever loved me.
我背叛了我父亲  我哥哥
I betrayed my father, my brother...
我的家园
my home.
我知道我做过什么
I know what I did.
也知道我那么做的原因
And I know why I did it.
但现在的我不一样了
And that's not who I am anymore.
好吗
Okay?
我不会让你失望
I won't let you down.
你确定
You sure?
因为如果我们成功了  时管局消失了
'Cause if we make it, and the TVA is gone,
也许有条时间线供你统治
there might be a timeline for you to rule.
那我就终于能快乐了
And then I'd finally be happy.
你呢
What about you?
这一切结束后  你会做什么
What will you do when this is all over?
我不知道
I don't know.
我也不知道
I don't know either.
也许
Maybe...
也许我们可以想清楚
Maybe we could figure it out...
一起想清楚
together.
也许吧
Maybe.
好了  下一步怎么做
Okay, so what's the next move?
必须扳倒时管局
The TVA needs to be brought down.
我们不知道创建者是谁  也不知道他们在哪
We don't know who created it or where they are,
但那东西知道
but that thing out there does.
它之前袭击我时  我和它连接了
When it hit me earlier, I linked to it.
虽然很短暂  但我瞥见了一些画面
It was brief, but I caught a glimpse of something,
如果我能接近它  我就能用魅术控制它
and I think if I can get close enough to it, I can enchant it,
它会带我去找在背后操纵一切的人
and it's gonna take me to whoever's behind all of this.
我留下来
I'm staying.
-洛基  我不知道能否成功  -你去我就去
- Loki, I don't know if this is gonna work. - You go, I go.
马上就要出现了  时间分支会在那里
It's happening, guys. The branch will be right out there.
我会替你们问候伦斯雷尔
I'll give your regards to Renslayer.
拜托了
Oh, please do.
你们想要出去的票吗
You boys want a ticket out of here?
什么  不  我们不走
What? No. We're staying here.
这是我们的家
This is our home.
你们确定吗  玉衡怎么办
Are you sure? What about Alioth?
我们已经撑了这么久  我们心里有数
We've survived this long. We know what we're doing.
洛基  你路上会用得到这个
Loki, you're gonna need this on your journey.
拿着
Go on.
祝好运
Good luck.
希望你找到你想要的
I hope you find what you're looking for.
看来你最后还是逃走了
Looks like you got away in the end.
我总能脱险
I always do.
你回到时管局会做什么
What will you do at the TVA?
把那里烧成灰
Burn it to the ground.
谢谢你的火花
Thanks for the spark.
回头见  洛基
Well, see you later, Loki.
谢谢你  我的朋友
Thank you, my friend.
你是我最喜欢的
You're my favorite.
时间分支出现时  玉衡会专注于它
When a branch appears, Alioth will focus on it.
那时我就会对玉衡施魅术
That's when I'll enchant it.
如果我们没时间等分支出现呢
What if we don't have time to wait for a branch?
那就得声东击西
We'll have to cause a distraction.
来抓我
Come and get me!
不  这边
No! This way!
来抓我啊
Come and get me!
他怎么做到的
How is he doing that?
我们比自己想的还要强大
I think we're stronger than we realize.
快
Go!
你这是干什么
What are you doing?
我们一起施魅术
We're gonna enchant it.
我不会
I don't know how.
你会
You do.
因为我们是一样的
Because we're the same!
光荣使命
Glorious purpose!
睁开眼睛
Open your eyes.